{
	"id": "Archimate-P01",
	"certName": "Archimate Part 1",
	"categories": [
		{
			"name": "Motivation layer",
			"questions": [				
				{
					"question": "What a Stakeholder in the Motivation layer represents?",
					"answer": "The role of an individual, team or organization that represents their interests in the effects of the architecture"
				},
				{
					"question": "What relations are possible between Motivation elements?",
					"answer": "Influence, each motivation element can influence other motivation elements"
				},
				{
					"question": "What relations are possible between Driver and Assessment?",
					"answer": "Association, a Driver may be associated with an Assessment and an Assessment may be associated with a Driver"
				},
				{
					"question": "What relations are possible between Outcome and Goal?",
					"answer": "Outcome realizes Goal"
				},
				{
					"question": "What elements may be associated with a Driver?",
					"answer": "Driver may be associated with Assessment and Goal"
				}
			]
		},
		{
			"name": "Strategy layer",
			"questions": [
				{
					"question": "What elements are part of the Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "1. Course of action; 2. Resource; 3. Capability; 4. Value Stream"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are the structure elements of the Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "1. Resource"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are the behavior elements of the Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "1. Course of action; 2. Value Stream; 3. Capability"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are the strategy behavior elements of the Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "1. Value Stream; 2. Capability"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is a Resource in the Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "An asset owned or controlled by an individual or an organization"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is the categories of a Resource in the Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "1. Tangible assets; 2. Intangible assets; 3. Human assets"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are some examples of tangible asset category for a Resource in the Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "Financial assets (money); Physical assets (Plant, equipment)"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are some examples of intangible asset category for a Resource in the Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "Technology assets (patents, copyrights); Reputation assets (brand, relationships); Culture assets"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is the preferred way to name a Resource in the Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "Noun"
				},
				{
					"question": "What a Capability in the Strategy layer represents?",
					"answer": "Represents an ability that an active structure element, such as an organization, person, or system, possesses"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is a Capability in the Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "what the enterprise can (is able to) do (now or in the future)"
				},
				{
					"question": "How is realized a Capability in the Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "Through a combination of organization, people, processes, information, and technology"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is the preferred way to name a Capability in the Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "it should be expressed as a compound noun or gerund (-ing form of verb); e.g., “Risk Management”, “Market Development”"
				},
				{
					"question": "What a Value Stream in the Strategy layer represents?",
					"answer": "Represents a sequence of activities that creates an overall result for a customer, stakeholder or end user"
				},
				{
					"question": "How should be defined a Value Stream in the Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "Always from the perspective of the stakeholder (customer, end user or recipient of the product/service)"
				},
				{
					"question": "What a Value Stream in the Strategy layer is composed of?",
					"answer": "Value-adding activities known as value (stream) stages"
				},
				{
					"question": "How are Value Streams in the Strategy layer realized?",
					"answer": "Realized by business processes"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is the preferred way to name a Value Stream in the Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "using a verb-noun construct in the active tense; e.g., “Acquire Insurance Product”."
				},
				{
					"question": "What a Course of Action in the Strategy layer represents?",
					"answer": "Represents an approach or plan for configuring some capabilities and resources of the enterprise, undertaken to achieve some goal"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are the categories of Course of Action in the Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "1. Strategies; 2. Tatics"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are the differences between the categories of Course of Action in the Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "Strategies tend to be long-term and fairly broad in scope while tatics tend to be shorter-term and narrower in scope"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are the possible relations between a Resource and a Strategy Behavior Element?",
					"answer": "A Resource is assigned to a Strategy Behavior Element. If un resource is assigned to the capability, it means that the resource is required for tha capability to work and exist"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are the possible relations between a Strategy Behavior Element and a Course of Action?",
					"answer": "A Strategy Behavior Element can either serve or realize a Course of Action"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are the possible relations between a Course of Action and a Course of Action?",
					"answer": "triggers/flows to/serve"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are the possible relations between a Strategy Behavior Element and a Strategy Behavior Element?",
					"answer": "triggers/flows to/serve"
				}
			]
		},
		{
			"name": "Business layer",
			"questions": [
				{
					"question": "What elements are part of the Business Layer Internal Active Structure?",
					"answer": "1. Business Role; 2. Business Actor; 3. Business Collaboration"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is a Business Actor?",
					"answer": "Represents a business entity capable of performing behavior"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are some examples of a Business Actor?",
					"answer": "Person, Business Unit, Organizations"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is the preferred way to name a Business Actor?",
					"answer": "Noun"
				},
				{
					"question": "What a Business Role represents?",
					"answer": "Represents the responsibility for performing specific behavior, to which an actor can be assigned, or the part an actor plays in particular action or event"
				},
				{
					"question": "What happens when a Business Actor is assigned to a Business Role?",
					"answer": "The Business Actor becomes responsible for performing the behavior, either by doing it himself or delegating it to somebody else"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is the relation between Business Role and Business Processes or Business Functions?",
					"answer": "A Business Role may be assigned to one or more Business Processes or Business Functions"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is the relation between Business Role and Business Actor?",
					"answer": "A Business Actor may be assigned to one or more Business Roles"
				},
				{
					"question": "What a Business Collaboration represents?",
					"answer": "Represents an aggregated of two or more business internal active structure elements that work together to perform collective behavior"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is a Business Collaboration?",
					"answer": "A Business Collaboration is a (possibly temporary) collection of business roles, actors, or other collaborations within an organization which perform collaborative behavior (interactions)"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is the preferred way to name a Business Collaboration?",
					"answer": "Noun but it can be unname also"
				},
				{
					"question": "What a Business Interface represents?",
					"answer": "Represents a point of access where business service are made available to the environment"
				},
				{
					"question": "What a Business Interface does?",
					"answer": "It exposes the functionality of a Business Service to other Business Roles or Business Actors"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is the relation between Business Interface and Business Service?",
					"answer": "A Business Interface may be assigned to one or more Business Services"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are some examples of Business Interface?",
					"answer": "Telephone, Internet, Local office"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is the preferred way to name a Business Interface?",
					"answer": "Noun"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are the Business Internal Behavior Elements?",
					"answer": "1. Business Process; 2. Business Function; 3. Business Interaction"
				},
				{
					"question": "What a Business Process represents?",
					"answer": "Represents a sequence of business behaviors that achieves a specific result such as a defined set of products or business services"
				},
				{
					"question": "What a Business Process describes?",
					"answer": "Describes the internal behavior performed by a business role that is required to produce a set of products and services"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is the difference between Business Process and Business Function?",
					"answer": "Business Process describes some kind of 'flow' of activities, whereas Business Function group activities according to required skills, knowledge, resources, etc."
				},
				{
					"question": "How do we know the Business Process is being performed manually or automatically?",
					"answer": "If a Business Role is assigned to the Business Process it is being done automatically; if it is realized by an Application Process is automatically"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is the preferred way to name a Business Process?",
					"answer": "Noun or verb-noun combination and may include the word 'process'"
				},
				{
					"question": "What a Business Function represents?",
					"answer": "Represents a collection of business behavior based on a chosen set of criteria such as required business resources and/or competencies, and is managed or performed as a whole"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is the relationship between a Business Function and a Capability?",
					"answer": "Business Function can realize capabilities"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is the relationship between a Business Function and other Business Behavior elements?",
					"answer": "Business Function can trigger o be triggered by a Business Behavior element"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is the relationship between a Business Function and a Business Service?",
					"answer": "Business Function may realize one or more Business Services"
				},
				{
					"question": "What elements may serve a Business Function?",
					"answer": "Business Function may be served by Business, Application, or Technology services"
				},
				{
					"question": "What elements may be assigned to Business Function?",
					"answer": "A Business Role may be assigned to a Business Function"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is the recommendation about Business Function name?",
					"answer": "It should clearly define what it does, well-defined behavior"
				},
				{
					"question": "What a Business Interaction represents?",
					"answer": "Represents a unir of collective business behavior performed by (a collaboration of) two or more business actors, business roles, or business collaborations"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is the relationship between a Business Interaction and other Business Behavior elements?",
					"answer": "Business Interaction can trigger o be triggered by a Business Behavior element"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is the relationship between a Business Interaction and a Business Service?",
					"answer": "A Business interaction may realize one or more business services"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is the recommendation about Business Interaction name?",
					"answer": "A verb in the simple past tense"
				},
				{
					"question": "What a Business Event represents?",
					"answer": "Represents a business-related state change"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is the preferred way to name a Business Event?",
					"answer": "Verb in the perfect tense"
				},
				{
					"question": "What a Business Event triggers/flows or is triggered by?",
					"answer": "Business Service, Business Internal Behavior Element, and other Business Events"
				},
				{
					"question": "What a Business Service represents?",
					"answer": "Represents explicitly defined behavior that a Business Role, Business Actor, or Business Collaboration exposes to its environment"
				},
				{
					"question": "How can a Business Service be accessed?",
					"answer": "Business Services are accessed through Business Interface"
				},
				{
					"question": "What may be the relation between a Business Service and a Business Interface?",
					"answer": "Business Interface is assigned to a Business Service"
				},
				{
					"question": "What a Business Object represents?",
					"answer": "A concept used within a particular business domain"
				},
				{
					"question": "What a Business Object usually models?",
					"answer": "It models an object type of which multiple instances may exist in operations"
				},
				{
					"question": "What Business Elements may access Business Objects?",
					"answer": "1. Business Process; 2. Business Function; 3. Business Interaction; 4. Business Event; 5. Business Service"
				},
				{
					"question": "What a Contrat represents?",
					"answer": "Formal or informal specification of an agreement between a provider and a consumer that specifies the rights and obligations associated with a product and establishes functional and non-functional parameters for interaction"
				},
				{
					"question": "What relationship does has a Contrat with a Business Object?",
					"answer": "A Contrat is an specialization of a Business Object"
				},
				{
					"question": "What relationship does has a Contrat with a Business Object?",
					"answer": "A Contrat is an specialization of a Business Object"
				},
				{
					"question": "What relationship may has a Contrat with a Business Product?",
					"answer": "A Contrat may have an aggregation relationship with a Product"
				},
				{
					"question": "What relationship may has a Contrat with a Business Product?",
					"answer": "A Contrat may have an aggregation relationship with a Product"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is the preferred way to name a Contrat?",
					"answer": "Noun"
				},
				{
					"question": "What a Representations represents?",
					"answer": "A perceptible form of the information carried by a Business Object"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are the composite elements of Business Layer?",
					"answer": "1. Product"
				},
				{
					"question": "What a Business Product represents?",
					"answer": "Coherent collection of services and/or passive structure elements, accompanied by a contract, which is offered as a whole to (internal or external) customers"
				}

			]
		},
		{
			"name": "Implementation adn Strategy layer",
			"questions": [
				{
					"question": "What does the Implementation and Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "It expresses the required changes in enterprise"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are the elements of the Implementation and Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "1. Plateau; 2. Gap; 3. Deliverable; 4. Work package; 5. Implementation event"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are the composite elements of the Implementation and Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "1. Plateau"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are the Passive structure elements of the Implementation and Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "1. Gap; 2. Deliverable"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are the Internal Behavior elements of the Implementation and Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "1. Work Package"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are the Event of the Implementation and Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "1. Implementatio Event"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is a Work package of the Implementation and Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "Is a unique one-off process that produces defined results"
				},
				{
					"question": "What does a Work package represents in the Implementation and Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "A series of actions identified and designed to achieve specific results within specified time and resource constraints"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are the characteristics of Work package in the Implementation and Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "1. Has a start and end date; 2. Produces defined results (Goals, Outcomes, Deliverables)"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Work package in the Implementation and Strategy layer used for?",
					"answer": "Work or task performed within projects. programs, project portfolio and agile"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Implement Event in the Implementation and Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "Changes an implementation-related state"
				},
				{
					"question": "What does a Implement Event represents in the Implementation and Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "Instantaneous state change related to implementation or migration"
				},
				{
					"question": "What a Implement Event represents in the Implementation and Strategy layer may access to?",
					"answer": "Deliverables"
				},
				{
					"question": "What a Implement Event represents in the Implementation and Strategy layer may trigger or be triggered by?",
					"answer": "1. Work Packages; 2. Plateaus"
				},
				{
					"question": "What a Implement Event represents in the Implementation and Strategy layer may be associated with?",
					"answer": "Any core element"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is the recommendation regards the name of Implement Event in the Implementation and Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "Should be formulated as a verb in perfect tense"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is a Deliverable in the Implementation and Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "Is a result produced by a Work Package"
				},
				{
					"question": "What does a Deliverable in the Implementation and Strategy layer represents?",
					"answer": "A precisely defined result of a Work Package"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is a characteristic of Deliverable in the Implementation and Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "Often contractually specified and in turn formally reviewed, agreed and signed off by the stakeholder"
				},
				{
					"question": "What a Deliverable in the Implementation and Strategy layer may be?",
					"answer": "May be a tangible document, an intagible organizational change or a implementation of an Enterprise Architecture"
				},
				{
					"question": "What a Gap in the Implementation and Strategy layer defines?",
					"answer": "Defines the differences between two Plateaus"
				},
				{
					"question": "What does Gap in the Implementation and Strategy layer represents?",
					"answer": "A statement of difference between two Plateaus as well as between the Baseline and Target architecture"
				},
				{
					"question": "What elements are associated with Gaps of Implementation and Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "two Plateaus, two consecutive transitions"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is a Plateau in Implementation and Strategy layer?",
					"answer": "Transition periods between baseline and target architecture"
				},
				{
					"question": "What does a Plateau in Implementation and Strategy layer represents?",
					"answer": "It represents a relatively stable state of the Enterprise Architecture that exists during a limited period of time"
				},
				{
					"question": "What does a Plateau in Implementation and Strategy layer allows?",
					"answer": "Group Work Packagess and projects into a Transition Architecture of managed portfolios and programs"
				}
			]
		}
	]
}